

# JUSTIN WALLACE



Two truths and a lie: I built out a Sprinter van and lived in it for three years. I did three tours in Iraq with the US Navy. I wrote my first website using Notepad when I was 12 years old (it was bad). Stumped? *They're all true*. I'm honest, humble, hard working, and above all else, *in love with the entire development process*. A perfect addition to your team.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Webstacks

Software Engineer L2 (February 2022 - Current)

- Created and managed the Webstacks UI library/template repository utilizing Typescript, MUI, Styled Components, and Storybook. It was enineered using a unique style of atomic CSS in JS that streamlines the development and training process.
- As the team lead for the OctoML dev team, I lead the efforts in creating a headless website (OctoML.ai) utilizing Dato, Gatsby, and Typescript. Responsible for peer and junior code reviews, sprint planning, and both technical and UX design reviews.
- In a team of six, helped develop the new and improved headless Webstacks marketing (Webstacks.com) site using Gastby, Contentful (GraphQL), and Typescript.
- Worked in an Agile environment with small teams developing modern websites and UI
  experiences for innovative tech companies such as Calendly and Freshworks seeing a
  consistent increase in engagement and conversions.

#### Fidelitas Development

Web Design/Development Intern (December 2019 - April 2020)

- Designed a responsive WordPress website (Kodiaklife.com) to provide outdoor survival information and revenue through affiliate links.
- Designed and developed pages and graphics for Office1.com following strict brand guidelines, improving overall aesthetic and UX of the site creating a CTA click-rate increase of 21% over 4 months.

### American Alpine Club, San Diego Chapter

Director of Media (January 2019 - January 2020)

• Designed print materials and social media posts to promote events and membership, which led to sold-out fundraisers and more than a 31% increase in membership.

#### **United States Navy**

Aviation Maintenance Manager (July 2006 - January 2020)

 Managed 1112 Sailors and civilians in the scheduled and unscheduled maintenance of 42 MH-60S helicopters resulting in a 98% mission completion rate.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Platt College San Diego (San Diego, CA)

BAS Web Design & Development | 4.0 GPA
AAS in Digital Media | 4.0 GPA

October 2021 - October 2022 January 2020 - August 2021

## **SKILLS**

Golang (Go)	ESlint/Prettier	NodeJS	GraphQL
Typescript	Responsive CSS	NextJS/Gatsby	React/Redux
CLI/NPM/GIT	Javascript (ES8+)	REST APIs	Webpack/Babel
Storybook	UX/UI Design	MUI	Styled Components







